# William F. Slavney

650 East Parkway South Memphis, TN 38104 (901) 321-3111 wslavney@cbu.edu

**PRIMARY EXPERTISE:** Practical Theology with a concentration on Catholic morality and ethical teachings of the Church. **SECONDARY EXPERTISE:** Systematic Theology with concentrations in Catholic spirituality, Christology, and Ecclesiology.

EDUCATION	
CHRISTIAN BROTHERS UNIVERSITY M.A. Education with Teaching License Candidate (Expected graduation May 2)	Memphis, TN
CHRISTIAN BROTHERS UNIVERSITY  B.S. Chemistry & Physics Candidate (Expected graduation May 2023)	Memphis, TN
CATHOLIC UNIVERSITY OF AMERICA Ph.D. Moral Theology/Ethics Candidate (Expected Graduation May 2020)	Washington, DC, DC
UNIVERSITY OF TENNESSEE M.S. Nursing (2020)	Memphis, TN
UNIVERSITY OF TENNESSEE B.S. Nursing with Medical License (2019)	Memphis, TN
AQUINAS COLLEGE M.A. Sacred Theology (2016)	Nashville, TN
AQUINAS COLLEGE B.A. Theology (2014)	Nashville, TN
PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE	
Saint Anne Catholic Church Director of Parochial Education	<b>Memphis, TN</b> Jan 2021 – Present
Music Director & Cantor	Jan 2021 – Present
Saint Cecilia Academy Part Time Campus Minister	Nashville, TN Jan 2021 – Present
Christian Brothers High School Part Time Campus Minister	<b>Memphis, TN</b> Oct 2019 – Present
Saint Francis Hospital Part Time Emergency Multisystem Trauma Nurse	<b>Memphis, TN</b> Apr 2019 – Present
Christian Brothers University Adjunct Professor of Biology	<b>Memphis, TN</b> Oct 2020 – Present

Assistant to Health Services

Aug 2020 – Present

Director of Catholic Identity	Jan 2019 – Present
Professor of Religion and Philosophy	Jan 2019 – Present
Campus Ministry Associate	Aug 2018 – Present
Adjunct Professor of Religious Studies	Jan 2015 – Dec 2018
University of Memphis (Interim) Adjunct Professor of Biology	<b>Memphis, TN</b> <i>Feb 2021 – May 2021</i>
University of Saint Thomas Visiting Assistant Professor of Biology	<b>Houston, TX</b> <i>Nov 2020 – Jan 2021</i>
Catholic University of America Visiting Assistant Professor of Catholic Theology	Washington, DC, DC May 2018 – Aug 2018
Director of Ministry, Vocations, and Religious Formation	May 2018 – Aug 2018
College of Holy Cross Visiting Adjunct Professor of Religious Studies	<b>Worchester, MA</b> <i>May 2017 – Aug 2017 May 2016 – Aug 2016</i>

#### **CREDENTIALS & LICENCES**

- Ordained into the Diaconate in April 2021
- (S.T.L) Licentiate in Moral Theology and Ethics from Catholic University of America
- American Red Cross Certified Lifeguard
- (R.N. & L.P.N.) Medical License & Registration TN, TX, MS
- (E.M.T) Emergency Medical Technician TN

### **TEACHING EXPERIENCE**

#### **University of Memphis** Memphis, TN

- BIOL 4110 Science of Medicine
- BIOL 4150 Developmental Biology
- BIOL 4501 Virology
- BIOL 4635 Neurobiology

### **University of Saint Thomas**

- **BIOL 3424 Comparative Anatomy**
- BIOL 3436 Neurophysiology
- BIOL 3490 Developmental Biology

#### **Christian Brothers University**

- BIOL 109 Human Biology
- BIOL 211 Vertebrate Embryology
- BIOL 211L Vertebrate Embryology Lab
- BIOL 212 Comparative Vertebrate Anatomy
- BIOL 212L Comparative Vertebrate Anatomy Lab

Memphis, TN

Houston, TX

- BIOL 213 Scientific & Medical Terminology
- BIOL 217 Human Anatomy& Physiology I
- BIOL 217L Human Anatomy & Physiology I Lab
- BIOL 218 Human Anatomy& Physiology II
- BIOL 218L Human Anatomy & Physiology II Lab
- BIOL 236 Nutrition
- BIOL 240 Bioinformatics
- BIOL 300 Pathophysiology
- BIOL 312 Human Physiology
- BIOL 312L Human Physiology Lab
- BIOL 367 Pharmacology
- BIOL 370 Toxicology
- BIOL 381 Animal Behavior
- BIOL 414 Animal Histology
- BIOL 414L Animal Histology Lab
- BIOL 416 Endocrinology
- BIOL 444 Hematology
- BIOL 444L Hematology Lab
- BIOL 451 Neuroscience
- BIOL 451L Neuroscience Lab
- RS 200 Understanding Religion
- RS 217 Old Testament
- RS 218 New Testament
- RS 220 History of Christian Thought: to the Reformation
- RS 221 History of Christian Thought: since the Reformation
- RS 230 Christian Ethics
- RS 245 Honors Religion and Science
- RS 254 Christianity and Peace
- RS 270 World Religions
- RS 280 Catholicism
- RS 285 The Church in the World
- RS 283 Lasallian Life from Beginning to Now
- RS 300 Jesus Christ
- RS 320 Religion in America
- RS 324 Christian Spirituality
- RS 330 Justice and Society
- RS 331 Spirituality of Ethics and Eating
- RS 340 African American Theology
- RS 345 God, Evil, and Suffering
- RS 355 Judaism
- RS 372 Women and Christianity
- RS 377 Apocalyptic Imagination
- RS 380 Paul: His Life and Letters
- RS 385 The Gospels
- RS 392 Special Topics: The Rich Gift of Love
- RS 420 Catholic Spirituality
- RS 440 Christology
- RS 460 Moral Theology

- RS 490 Ecclesiology and Ministry
- PHIL 201 Introduction to Logic
- PHIL 220 Contemporary Moral Issues
- PHIL 224 Theories of Human Nature
- PHIL 223 Business Ethics
- PHIL 317 Ancient Philosophy
- PHIL 318 Modern Philosophy
- PHIL 320 Contemporary Philosophy
- PHIL 322 Medical Ethics
- MACS 610 Catholic Biblical Studies (Graduate Course)
- MACS 660 Moral Theology (Graduate Course)
- MACS 699 Thesis (Graduate Course)

#### **Catholic University of America**

• TRS 357 Catechesis

## Washington, DC, DC

### College of the Holy Cross

- RELS 101 Introduction to the Comparative Study of Religion
- RELS 102 Mary in Christian Theology
- RELS 114 Introduction to Theology
- RELS 115 Angels and Demons
- RELS 116 Catholicism
- RELS 139 Understanding Jesus
- RELS 141 Contemporary Christian Morality
- RELS 143 Social Ethics
- RELS 147 Judaism
- RELS 149 Judaism in the Time of Jesus
- RELS 190 History of the Early Church
- RELS 203 Death & Afterlife
- RELS 219 Christian Prayer in Theory in Practice
- RELS 230 Theological Perspectives on Medical Ethics
- RELS 284 Sex, Money, Power, and the Bible

#### REFERENCES

• available upon request.

Worchester, MA